<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Matt Hammond Inc</title><link>https://matthammond.com/</link><description>Recent content on Matt Hammond Inc</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 21:41:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matthammond.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aviation</title><link>https://matthammond.com/services/aviation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 21:41:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/services/aviation/</guid><description>Prior military professional with military aviation experience as well as civilian aviation experience in helicopters and fixed wing stateside and abroad.
Excellent personal skills, computer skills, professionalism, responsibility, reliability, and moral and ethical judgment. Consistently maintains a high degree of work principles while still remaining flexible and adaptive in dynamic environments.
Contract pilot for fixed wing. Cirrus Vision Jet SF-50 Contract pilot for rotary wing. BV-234 EC-145 EC-145e Bell 212 Operator for sUAS.</description></item><item><title>DevOps</title><link>https://matthammond.com/services/devops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 18:57:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/services/devops/</guid><description>Strong knowledge acquired in the areas of cyber network security analysis, DevOps tool administration, and information security system analysis. Expertise in implementing DevOps practices into IT organizations in a cost-efficient manner in compliance with the design. Skilled in analyzing security implications when integrating systems and data with third-party vendors/solutions considering data ownership, backups, policies around unauthorized data sharing, etc. Well-versed in various threats, vulnerabilities, and attacks. Proficient in evaluating mitigation controls and deterrent techniques to handle attacks efficiently.</description></item><item><title>Advisor</title><link>https://matthammond.com/services/advisor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 21:38:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/services/advisor/</guid><description>Retired military professional with expertise in military aviation and Special Operations.
Demonstrate excellent interpersonal skills, computer proficiency, professionalism, responsibility, reliability, and strong moral and ethical judgment. Consistently upholds high work standards while remaining adaptable in dynamic and austere environments.
Provides mentorship during military training, aiding in the creation of scenarios that simulate potential deployment situations.
Provide an insider&amp;rsquo;s view, sharing unique experiences and highlighting the vital role that staff and/or SOF plays in global events.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://matthammond.com/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/about/</guid><description>I am a prior military professional with military aviation experience and Special Operations experience. As well as civilian aviation experience in helicopters and fixed wing stateside and abroad. I have turned an interest, hobby, and passion of IT related content into a strong knowledge in the areas of cyber network security analysis, DevOps tool administration, and information security system analysis by completing Security+, CEH, and Splunk Core User certifications. I will be using Github and my website to continue my learning and as a place to implement what I learn.</description></item><item><title>Python Virtual Environments</title><link>https://matthammond.com/articles/2024/python-virtual-environments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/articles/2024/python-virtual-environments/</guid><description>Install pyenv and Setup Environment For full documentation on pyenv visit Github.
brew install pyenv Add the following to your .zshrc file. # Enable shims and autocompletion eval &amp;#34;$(pyenv init -)&amp;#34; eval &amp;#34;$(pyenv virtualenv-init -)&amp;#34; # Add pyenv to $PATH export PYENV_ROOT=&amp;#34;$HOME/.pyenv&amp;#34; [[ &amp;#34;:$PATH:&amp;#34; =~ &amp;#34;:$PYENV_ROOT/bin:&amp;#34; ]] || export PATH=&amp;#34;$PYENV_ROOT/bin:$PATH&amp;#34; Commands pyenv install -l: list versions for installation pyenv install &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;: install selected version pyenv virtualenv &amp;lt;version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;environment_name&amp;gt;: create virtual environment pyenv virtualenvs: list virtual environments pyenv activate &amp;lt;environment_name&amp;gt;: activate virtual environment source deactivate: deactivate virtual environment pyenv uninstall &amp;lt;environment_name or python version&amp;gt;: delete virtual environment or uninstall python version Autoload Virtual Environment Create .</description></item><item><title>Professional Email Signatures</title><link>https://matthammond.com/articles/2024/professional-email-signatures/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/articles/2024/professional-email-signatures/</guid><description>Intro Let&amp;rsquo;s create a professional looking signature for your email. This tutorial will give you step-by-step instructions on creating and deploying an email signature for iCloud (macOS Mail client and iPhone) along with Google. It may work for other providers such as Outlook, but has not been tested.
If you want a logo or photo in your signature, it is important that the image is available online and the location does not move.</description></item><item><title>Homebridge Restore Backup</title><link>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/homebridge-restore-backup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/homebridge-restore-backup/</guid><description>Issue When updating homebridge in docker with the onzu build, sometimes you may not be able to restore from your backup. I was able to restore via the command line; however, I had to manually reinstall my plugins. The good news is once you install the plugins via the Web UI, you do not have to reconfigure.
Fix Extract your homebridge-backup.tar.gz into a folder. Navigate to /var/lib/docker/volumes/homebridge_homebridge/_data (you may have to switch to root - sudo su).</description></item><item><title>Disable MacOS SSH Password Login</title><link>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/disable-macos-ssh-password-login/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/disable-macos-ssh-password-login/</guid><description>Create 000-hostname.conf in /etc/ssh/sshd_config.d
000-hostname.conf UsePAM no PasswordAuthentication no Restart SSH sudo launchctl stop com.openssh.sshd sudo launchctl start com.openssh.sshd</description></item><item><title>Crontab</title><link>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/crontab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/crontab/</guid><description># ┌───────────── minute (0 - 59) # │ ┌───────────── hour (0 - 23) # │ │ ┌───────────── day of month (1 - 31) # │ │ │ ┌───────────── month (1 - 12) # │ │ │ │ ┌───────────── day of week (0 - 6) (Sunday to Saturday; # │ │ │ │ │ 7 is also Sunday on some systems) # │ │ │ │ │ # │ │ │ │ │ # * * * * * command_to_execute https://crontab.</description></item><item><title>Regex</title><link>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/regex/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/regex/</guid><description>. - Any Character Except New Line \d - Digit (0-9) \D - Not a Digit (0-9) \w - Word Character (a-z, A-Z, 0-9, _) \W - Not a Word Character \s - Whitespace (space, tab, newline) \S - Not Whitespace (space, tab, newline) \b - Word Boundary \B - Not a Word Boundary ^ - Beginning of a String $ - End of a String [] - Matches Characters in brackets [^ ] - Matches Characters NOT in brackets | - Either Or ( ) - Group Quantifiers: * - 0 or More + - 1 or More ?</description></item><item><title>Mac Network Cli Snippets</title><link>https://matthammond.com/mac-network-cli-snippets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/mac-network-cli-snippets/</guid><description>ipconfig get ip address ipconfig getifaddr en0 get subnet mask ipconfig getoption en0 subnet_mask get dns server ipconfig getoption en0 domain_name_server get info about how en0 got its dhcp on ipconfig getpacket en0 renew dhcp lease ipconfig set en0 DHCP # or this ipconfig set en1 BOOTP &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ipconfig set en1 DHCP ifconfig en1 down &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ifconfig en1 up set a specific ip address ipconfig set en0 INFORM 192.168.1.160 ifconfig get network info ifconfig en0 set ip address and netmask ifconfig en0 inet 192.</description></item><item><title>Mac Snippets</title><link>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/mac-snippets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/mac-snippets/</guid><description>Code Snippets remove duplicates from $PATH typeset -U PATH link airport sudo ln -s /System/Library/PrivateFrameworks/Apple80211.framework/Versions/Current/Resources/airport /usr/local/bin/airport partition USB sudo diskutil partitionDisk /dev/disk2 4 GPT ExFAT Tails 32G APFS Keys 10M ExFAT Drive 1G ExFAT Go\ Drive R sudo diskutil apfs encryptVolume disk3s1 -user disk format USB diskutil erasedisk ExFAT GoDrive disk2 #format for Linux only diskutil erasedisk MS-DOS GODRIVE disk2 #format for Mac/Linux write image to usb sudo gdd if=~/Downloads/debian.iso of=/dev/disk2 status=progress bs=4M unload macfuse kernel sudo kextunload -b io.</description></item><item><title>Netcat Chat Server</title><link>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/netcat-chat-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/netcat-chat-server/</guid><description>Local Host netcat -l -p 1299 Connecting Host netcat localhost 1299</description></item><item><title>SSH Keys</title><link>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/ssh-keys/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/ssh-keys/</guid><description>create ssh key in terminal ssh-keygen -a 100 -t ed25519 -f ~/.ssh/id_ed25519 -C &amp;#34;john@example.com&amp;#34; -a: It’s the numbers of KDF (Key Derivation Function) rounds. Higher numbers result in slower passphrase verification, increasing the resistance to brute-force password cracking should the private-key be stolen. -t: Specifies the type of key to create, in our case the Ed25519. -f: Specify the filename of the generated key file. If you want it to be discovered automatically by the SSH agent, it must be stored in the default .</description></item><item><title>Steganography Payload</title><link>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/steganography-payload/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/articles/2023/steganography-payload/</guid><description>Create Payload create a bash script (i.e. payload.sh) #!/bin/bash echo &amp;#34;This is the payload script&amp;#34; transform script to base64 cat payload.sh | base64 | tr -d &amp;#39;\n&amp;#39; Embed Payload clear metadata from image exiftool -all= image.jpg load hash into image exiftool -Certificate=&amp;#39;base64 hash&amp;#39; image.jpg Execute Payload p=$(cat image.jpg | grep Cert -a | sed &amp;#39;s/&amp;lt;[^&amp;gt;]*&amp;gt;//g&amp;#39; | base64 -D);eval $p</description></item><item><title>Contact Me</title><link>https://matthammond.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/contact/</guid><description>If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out.
The quickest way to get in touch with me for questions is via email. Email me at contact@matthammond.com with any inquiries or suggestions you have.
Trouble emailing me? Use this form instead.</description></item></channel></rss>