<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Services on Matt Hammond Inc</title><link>https://matthammond.com/services/</link><description>Recent content in Services on Matt Hammond Inc</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 21:41:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matthammond.com/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aviation</title><link>https://matthammond.com/services/aviation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 21:41:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/services/aviation/</guid><description>Prior military professional with military aviation experience as well as civilian aviation experience in helicopters and fixed wing stateside and abroad.
Excellent personal skills, computer skills, professionalism, responsibility, reliability, and moral and ethical judgment. Consistently maintains a high degree of work principles while still remaining flexible and adaptive in dynamic environments.
Contract pilot for fixed wing. Cirrus Vision Jet SF-50 Contract pilot for rotary wing. BV-234 EC-145 EC-145e Bell 212 Operator for sUAS.</description></item><item><title>DevOps</title><link>https://matthammond.com/services/devops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 18:57:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/services/devops/</guid><description>Strong knowledge acquired in the areas of cyber network security analysis, DevOps tool administration, and information security system analysis. Expertise in implementing DevOps practices into IT organizations in a cost-efficient manner in compliance with the design. Skilled in analyzing security implications when integrating systems and data with third-party vendors/solutions considering data ownership, backups, policies around unauthorized data sharing, etc. Well-versed in various threats, vulnerabilities, and attacks. Proficient in evaluating mitigation controls and deterrent techniques to handle attacks efficiently.</description></item><item><title>Advisor</title><link>https://matthammond.com/services/advisor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 21:38:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://matthammond.com/services/advisor/</guid><description>Retired military professional with expertise in military aviation and Special Operations.
Demonstrate excellent interpersonal skills, computer proficiency, professionalism, responsibility, reliability, and strong moral and ethical judgment. Consistently upholds high work standards while remaining adaptable in dynamic and austere environments.
Provides mentorship during military training, aiding in the creation of scenarios that simulate potential deployment situations.
Provide an insider&amp;rsquo;s view, sharing unique experiences and highlighting the vital role that staff and/or SOF plays in global events.</description></item></channel></rss>